Guide to the James Rowland Angell, President of Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records, 1921-1937; Series I
  - International Student Committee (Box 115, Folder 1179)
  - Invitations, 1936-1937 (Box 115, Folder 1180-1181)
  - Invitations, engraved forms for President's receptions (Box 115, Folder 1182-1183)
  - Iowa, University of (Box 116, Folder 1184)
  - Irvine, Sir James Colquhoun, K.T.C.B.E. (Box 116, Folder 1185)
  - Italian Fellowship Exchange (Box 116, Folder 1186)
  - Italian students visit to Yale (Box 116, Folder 1187)
  - J (Box 116, Folder 1187-1189)
  - Japanese Collections, Yale Association of Japan (Box 116, Folder 1190)
  - Jefferson, Charles E. (Box 116, Folder 1191)
  - Jennings, Walter, Memorial Fund (Box 116, Folder 1192)
  - Jewish problem (Box 116, Folder 1193)
  - Jo (Box 116, Folder 1194)
  - Johnson, Frederick B. (Box 116, Folder 1195)
  - Johnson, Mrs. E. Newlands (Box 116, Folder 1196)
  - Jon (Box 117, Folder 1197)
  - Jones, Frederick S. (Box 117, Folder 1198)
  - Journal of Experimental Zoology (Box 117, Folder 1199)
  - Judd, Charles H. (Box 117, Folder 1200)
  - Judson Estate (Box 117, Folder 1201)
  - Junior Promenade (Box 117, Folder 1202)
  - K (Box 117, Folder 1203)
  - Karpinski Collection (Box 117, Folder 1204)
  - Ke (Box 117, Folder 1205-1206)
  - Keith, Allan-Rialto Fire (Box 117, Folder 1207)
  - Keller, Albert G. (Box 118, Folder 1208)
  - Kelsey, Clarence H. (Box 118, Folder 1209)
  - Ken (Box 118, Folder 1210)
  - Kent, Charles F. (Box 118, Folder 1211)
  - Kent Chemical Laboratory; Kent Hall: William Kent (Box 118, Folder 1212)
  - Kent School (Box 118, Folder 1213)
  - Keogh, Andrew (Box 118, Folder 1214)
  - Ki (Box 118, Folder 1215-1216)
  - Kl-Kp (Box 118, Folder 1217)
  - Kr (Box 118, Folder 1218)
  - Kraeling, Carl H. (Box 118, Folder 1219)
  - La (Box 119, Folder 1220-1223)
  - Laboratory fees (Box 119, Folder 1224)
  - Lafayette College, Proceedings of Conference of Trustees of Colleges and Universities (Box 119, Folder 1225)
  - Lang, Henry R., Bequest for the Alice Derby Lang Fund (Box 119, Folder 1226)
  - Laski, Harold J. (Box 119, Folder 1227)
  - Law School
    - 1922-1929 (Box 119, Folder 1228-1232)
    - 1930-1937 (Box 120, Folder 1233-1243)
    - Centennial program (Box 121, Folder 1244)
    - Combined course with Harvard Business (Box 121, Folder 1245)
    - Courses, five year program (Box 121, Folder 1246)
    - Deanship (Box 121, Folder 1247)
    - Dedication (Box 121, Folder 1248)
    - Faculty appointments, promotions, 1930-1936 (Box 121, Folder 1249-1253)
    - Faculty: Tuition, fellowships, scholarships, 1922-1925 (Box 122, Folder 1254)
    - Faculty: Tuition, fellowships, scholarships, 1927-1930 (Box 122, Folder 1255-1258)
    - Institute of International Law (Box 122, Folder 1259-1260)
    - Location of new buildings (Box 122, Folder 1261-1262)
    - Location of new buildings in connection with Institute of Human Relations
      General
      See: box 176, folder 1874-1875
    - Minutes, 1928-1933 (Box 122, Folder 1263-1266)
    - Minutes, 1934-1937 (Box 123, Folder 1267-1270)
    - Moore, Underhill (Box 123, Folder 1271-1272)
    - School of Jurisprudence, Plans for (Box 123, Folder 1273)
    - Study of mixed arbitral tribunals Guides to foreign law (Box 123, Folder 1274)
    - Tuition, fellowships, scholarships, 1929-1937 (Box 123, Folder 1275-1276)
    - Yale Law Journal (Box 123, Folder 1277)
  - Le (Box 123, Folder 1278)
  - League of Nations (Box 123, Folder 1279)
  - League of Nations (Box 124, Folder 1280)
  - League of Nations, Model (Box 124, Folder 1281)
  - Learned Societies, Meetings at Yale (Box 124, Folder 1282)
  - Leaves of absence (Box 124, Folder 1283)
  - Lecture Committee (Box 124, Folder 1284-1285)
  - Lee, Porter R., New York School of Social Work (Box 124, Folder 1286)
  - Len-Lev (Box 124, Folder 1287-1288)
  - Li (Box 124, Folder 1289-1291)
  - Liberal Arts College movement (Box 125, Folder 1292)
  - Liberal Club (Box 125, Folder 1293)
  - Library
    - 1921-1937 (Box 125, Folder 1294-1305)
    - Childs Fund-Blickling Homilies; Washington Irving Collection (Box 126, Folder 1306)
    - Class of 1865 memorabilia (Box 126, Folder 1307)
    - The James Fenimore Cooper Collection (Box 126, Folder 1308)
    - Committee Minutes, 1921-1932 (Box 126, Folder 1309-1314)
    - Committee Minutes, 1934-1937 (Box 126, Folder 1315-1316)
    - Committee on Periodical Subscriptions (Box 126, Folder 1317-1318)
    - President's Committee (Box 126, Folder 1319)
    - Committee on Staff and Appointments (Box 126, Folder 1320)
    - Committee on Staff and Appointments (Box 127, Folder 1321)
    - Conference of the American Library Association, 1931 (Box 127, Folder 1322)
  - Life Extension Institute (Box 127, Folder 1323)
  - Limitations of number of students (Box 127, Folder 1324)
  - Lincoln School (Box 127, Folder 1325)
  - Linguistic Institute (Box 127, Folder 1326-1328)
  - Liquor Control (Box 127, Folder 1329)
  - Lohmann, Carl A. (Box 127, Folder 1330)
  - Longmans, Green and Company (Box 127, Folder 1331)
  - Loomis, James Lee (Box 127, Folder 1332)
  - Lo (Box 127, Folder 1333-1335)
  - Loram, Charles T. (Box 128, Folder 1336-1339)
  - Louisiana State University (Box 128, Folder 1340)
  - Louisiana State University, The Southern Review, July 1935 (Box 128, Folder 1341)
  - Louvain University Library (Box 128, Folder 1342)
  - Lu (Box 128, Folder 1343-1344)
  - Ludington, Charles H. (Box 128, Folder 1345)
  - Ludington, Nicholas S. (Box 128, Folder 1345)
  - M (Box 129, Folder 1346)
  - Mah-Maq (Box 129, Folder 1347)
  - Mandell, Max (Russian instruction) (Box 129, Folder 1348)
  - Mann, Charles R. (Box 129, Folder 1349-1350)
  - Manufacturer's Association of Connecticut (Box 129, Folder 1351)
  - Mar (Box 129, Folder 1352)
  - Mas (Box 130, Folder 1353)
  - Mason, George Grant (Box 130, Folder 1354)
  - Mathematics Department (Box 130, Folder 1355-1356)
  - Mathematics Department, Departmental chairmen (Box 130, Folder 1357)
  - Mathews, Shailer (Box 130, Folder 1358)
  - Matriculation (Box 130, Folder 1359)
  - McA (Box 130, Folder 1360)
  - McClintock, Walter (Box 130, Folder 1361)
  - McCormick, Vance C. (Box 130, Folder 1362)
  - McD (Box 131, Folder 1363)
  - MacDonald, Helen Parrott, Estate of (Box 131, Folder 1364)
  - McGill University Centenary (Box 131, Folder 1365)
  - McK (Box 131, Folder 1366-1367)
  - McKee, Elmore (Box 131, Folder 1368)
  - McMillan, Philips Hamilton Fund (Box 131, Folder 1369)
  - Me (Box 131, Folder 1370)
  - Mechanical Engineering Department (Box 131, Folder 1371)
  - Medical School
    - 1920-1924 (Box 132, Folder 1372)
    - 1922-1925 (Box 132, Folder 1373-1374)
    - 1923-1927 (Box 132, Folder 1375)
    - 1925-1928 (Box 132, Folder 1376)
    - 1926-1928 (Box 132, Folder 1377)
    - 1928-1933 (Box 132, Folder 1378)
    - 1934-1935 (Box 132, Folder 1379)
    - 1935-1937 (Box 132, Folder 1380-1381)
    - Allen, Edgar, head of Anatomy Department (Box 133, Folder 1382)
    - Board of Permanent Officers Committee on Biological Sciences (Box 133, Folder 1383)
    - Bayne-Jones, Stanhope (Box 133, Folder 1384)
    - Brady Laboratory extension (Box 133, Folder 1385)
    - Budgets and Special Committee on Budgets (Box 133, Folder 1386)
    - Childs, Jane Coffin Memorial Fund (Box 133, Folder 1387)
    - Clinical Research and Teaching Fund (Box 133, Folder 1388)
    - Commission on Medical Education (Box 133, Folder 1389)
    - Committee (Box 133, Folder 1390)
    - Committee on Cost of Medical Care (Box 133, Folder 1391)
    - Committee on Cost of Medical Care, booklets and reports (Box 133, Folder 1392)
    - Deanship (Box 133, Folder 1393)
    - Department of Bacteriology (Box 133, Folder 1394)
    - Department of Bacteriology, Pathology and Public Health (Box 133, Folder 1395-1396)
    - Department of Pediatrics (Box 133, Folder 1397)
    - Department of Public Health (Box 133, Folder 1398)
    - Experimental studies in neurophysiology (Box 133, Folder 1399)
    - Full time (Box 133, Folder 1400)
    - General Education Board, gifts (Box 133, Folder 1401-1402)
    - Harvey, Samuel C. (Box 133, Folder 1403)
    - Hospital Building Plans, Human Welfare Group (Box 133, Folder 1404)
    - Journal of Biology and Medicine (Box 133, Folder 1405)
    - Medical treatment for students, emergency operations and hospital expenses (Box 134, Folder 1406)
    - Minutes, 1921-1937 (Box 134, Folder 1407-1409)
    - New Haven Hospital (Box 135, Folder 1410-1414)
    - Prudential Committee Minutes (Box 135, Folder 1415-1416)
    - Psychiatric Hospital (Box 135, Folder 1417-1418)
    - University Department of Health (Box 135, Folder 1419-1420)
    - Reorganization plans (Box 135, Folder 1421)
    - Report, 1936-1937 (Box 135, Folder 1422)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, grant to Professor Cowgill, research on physiology of vitamins (Box 135, Folder 1423)
    - Sheffield Scientific School Agreement (Box 135, Folder 1424)
    - Sterling Hall of Medicine, dedication (Box 135, Folder 1425)
    - Winslow, Charles Edward A. (Box 135, Folder 1426)
  - Memorial Day (Box 136, Folder 1427)
  - Memorials, Committee on (Box 136, Folder 1428)
  - Mendell, Clarence W. (Box 136, Folder 1429-1430)
  - Mental Hygiene (Box 136, Folder 1431-1432)
  - Mental Hygiene, Anniversary Meeting 1933, Sprague Hall (Box 136, Folder 1433-1434)
  - Mental Hygiene, Connecticut Society and International Committee (Box 136, Folder 1435-1437)
  - Mental Hygiene, Connecticut Society and International Committee (Box 137, Folder 1438-1445)
  - Mental Hygiene, Connecticut Society and International Committee (Box 138, Folder 1446-1447)
  - Mer (Box 138, Folder 1448-1449)
  - Merriam, John C. (Box 138, Folder 1450)
  - Metallurgy Department, formerly Department of Mining and Metallurgy (Box 138, Folder 1451)
  - Metz Research Fellow (Box 138, Folder 1452)
  - Meyer, Eugene Jr. Public Service Fund (Box 138, Folder 1453)
  - Meyers, Walter (Box 138, Folder 1454)
  - Mi (Box 138, Folder 1455-1456)
  - Mi (Box 139, Folder 1457-1458)
  - Michigan, University of (Box 139, Folder 1459)
  - Middlebury College (Box 139, Folder 1460)
  - Military Science and Tactics, Yale R.O.T.C. (Box 139, Folder 1461-1466)
  - Military Science and Tactics, Yale R.O.T.C. (Box 140, Folder 1467-1471)
  - Military Science and Tactics, R.O.T.C. conference with President H.W. Dodd, Princeton, regarding credit (Box 140, Folder 1472)
  - Military Training Corps Association (Yale Tuition Scholarship) (Box 140, Folder 1473)
  - Miller (Box 140, Folder 1474)
  - Miller, Mrs. Frank, Miller Scholarship (Box 140, Folder 1475)
  - Millikan, Robert A. (Box 140, Folder 1476)
  - Mo (Box 140, Folder 1477)
  - Moore, Clifford H. (Box 141, Folder 1478)
  - Mor (Box 141, Folder 1479)
  - Morris, Mr. and Mrs. Dave H. (Box 141, Folder 1480)
  - Morsman, Joseph J. (Box 141, Folder 1481)
  - Mount Holyoke College (Box 141, Folder 1482)
  - Moving pictures (Box 141, Folder 1483)
  - Mu (Box 141, Folder 1484)
  - Mur (Box 141, Folder 1485)
  - Murphy, Fred T. (Box 141, Folder 1486)
  - Murphy, John Speed Scholarships (Box 141, Folder 1487)
  - Museum Committee (Box 141, Folder 1488)
  - Museum Training, American Association of Museums (Box 141, Folder 1489)
  - Music School (Box 141, Folder 1490)
  - Music School, Charles H. Dilson Scholarship (Box 141, Folder 1491)
  - Music School, minutes (Box 141, Folder 1492)
  - N (Box 142, Folder 1493-1946)
  - Nathan Hale Inn, Tapping Reeve Inn (Box 142, Folder 1497)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research (Box 142, Folder 1498)
  - National Civic Federation (Box 142, Folder 1499)
  - National Council on Religion in High Education (Box 142, Folder 1500)
  - National Education Association (Box 142, Folder 1501-1503)
  - National Institute of Public Affairs (Box 143, Folder 1504)
  - National Recovery Association (Box 143, Folder 1505)
  - National Research Council Fellowships (Box 143, Folder 1506)
  - National Student Forum (Box 143, Folder 1507)
  - National Tuberculosis Association (Box 143, Folder 1508)
  - Nature Preserve (Box 143, Folder 1509)
  - Negroes at Yale (Box 143, Folder 1510)
  - Nettleton, George H. (Box 143, Folder 1511)
  - Naval Reserve Officers Training Corps (Box 143, Folder 1512-1516)
  - Naval Reserve Officers' Training Corps (Box 144, Folder 1517)
  - Naval Reserve Officers' Training Corps, Berrien, Captain F.D. (Box 144, Folder 1518)
  - Naval Reserve Officers' Training Corps, Military Naval Units (Box 144, Folder 1519)
  - Naval Reserve Officers' Training Corps, President of Special Committee on Agreement with Government (Box 144, Folder 1520)
  - Naval Reserve Officers' Training Corps, Signal Corps Unit (Box 144, Folder 1521)
  - New (Box 144, Folder 1522-1524)
  - Newberry Memorial Organ, Woolsey Hall (Box 144, Folder 1525)
  - New England Associated Yale Clubs (Box 144, Folder 1526)
  - New England Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools (Box 144, Folder 1527-1528)
  - New Haven (Box 145, Folder 1529-1533)
  - New Haven Broadcasting Station (Box 145, Folder 1534)
  - New Haven Colony Historical Society (Box 145, Folder 1535)
  - New Haven Community Chest, Incorporated (Box 145, Folder 1536)
  - New Haven Evening Register (Box 145, Folder 1537)
  - New Haven Foundation (Box 145, Folder 1538)
  - New Haven Symphony Orchestra (Box 145, Folder 1539)
  - New York Genealogical and Biographical Society (Box 145, Folder 1540)
  - New York, New School for Social Research (Box 145, Folder 1541)
  - New York School of Social Work (Box 145, Folder 1542)
  - New York Times (Box 145, Folder 1543)
  - New York University, Educational Conference, Waldorf Astoria, 1932 November 15-17 (Box 146, Folder 1544-1545)
  - New York University, Honorary Degree conferred, 1934 January 13 (Box 146, Folder 1546)
  - Ni (Box 146, Folder 1547)
  - No (Box 146, Folder 1548)
  - No-Ny (Box 146, Folder 1549)
  - North Carolina, University of (Box 146, Folder 1550)
  - Noyes, Edward Simpson (Box 146, Folder 1551)
  - Nursing School
    - 1922-1926 (Box 147, Folder 1552-1553)
    - 1923-1927 (Box 147, Folder 1554)
    - 1923-1928 (Box 147, Folder 1555)
    - 1924 January 24 (Box 147, Folder 1556)
    - 1925-1934 (Box 147, Folder 1557-1560)
    - 1933-1935 (Box 147, Folder 1561-1561)
    - 1935-1937 (Box 148, Folder 1562)
    - Committee on Budget (Box 148, Folder 1563)
    - Deanship (Box 148, Folder 1564)
    - Minutes of the Administrative Committee, 1931-1934 (Box 148, Folder 1565-1571)
    - Minutes of the Administrative Committee, 1935-1937 (Box 149, Folder 1572-1574)
    - Minutes of the Faculty and Institutional Adjustments Committee, 1931-1932 (Box 149, Folder 1575)
    - Minutes of the Faculty Council, 1931-1935 (Box 149, Folder 1576)
  - O (Box 149, Folder 1577-1580)
  - Observatory, Yale (Box 149, Folder 1579-1580)
  - Ol (Box 150, Folder 1581-1583)
  - Old Age Pension (Box 150, Folder 1584)
  - Oriental and Classical Research (Box 150, Folder 1585)
  - Oriental Fellowship, O.O.Kellogg-C.Rahn (Box 150, Folder 1586)
  - Oriental Studies (Box 150, Folder 1587)
  - Oriental Studies, Far Eastern Studies Program (Box 150, Folder 1588)
  - Osborn, Wilmott A. (Box 150, Folder 1589)
  - Oviatt, Edwin (Box 150, Folder 1590)
  - Owen, W.H., Coin Collection (Box 150, Folder 1591)
  - P (Box 151, Folder 1592-1594)
  - Pacific Relations, Institute of (Box 151, Folder 1595-1601)
  - Pacific Relations, Institute of (Box 152, Folder 1602-1603)
  - Pan-Pacific Scientific Congress (Box 152, Folder 1604)
  - Par (Box 152, Folder 1605)
  - Parents Publishing Association, Inc. (Box 152, Folder 1606-1608)
  - Parsons, Francis (Box 152, Folder 1609)
  - Patent protection for Yale (Box 152, Folder 1610)
  - Payne Study and Experiment Fund (Box 152, Folder 1611)
  - Pe (Box 153, Folder 1612-1614)
  - Peabody Museum
    - Advisory Council (Box 153, Folder 1615)
    - Directors, trustees, meetings (Box 153, Folder 1616-1618)
    - Directors, trustees, meetings (Box 154, Folder 1619-1620)
    - New buildings (Box 154, Folder 1621)
    - Schuchert Collection (Box 154, Folder 1623)
    - Stone Age Collection-Payne, Edward (Box 154, Folder 1624)
    - Successor to Richard S. Lull (Box 154, Folder 1625)
    - Yale Oceanographic Expedition (Box 154, Folder 1626)
  - Pearson, E.J. Fund, New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad employees (Box 155, Folder 1627)
  - Pennsylvania, University of (Box 155, Folder 1628)
  - Perpetual Encyclopedia (Box 155, Folder 1629)
  - Personnel Department, correspondence and memoranda (Box 155, Folder 1630-1631)
  - Personnel Research Federation (Box 155, Folder 1632-1633)
  - Personnel Study Department (Box 155, Folder 1634-1635)
  - Pet (Box 156, Folder 1636)
  - Pf (Box 156, Folder 1637-1639)
  - Pharmacology and Toxicology Department (Box 156, Folder 1640)
  - Phelps, William Lyon (Box 156, Folder 1641)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 156, Folder 1642-1644)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 157, Folder 1645-1649)
  - Philippines, University of the (Box 157, Folder 1650)
  - Philosophy Department (Box 157, Folder 1651-1652)
  - Philosophy and Psychology Department (Box 158, Folder 1653-1654)
  - Physics Department (Box 158, Folder 1655-1656)
  - Physiological Chemistry, Mendel, L.B. (Box 158, Folder 1657)
  - Physiological Sciences Department (Box 158, Folder 1658-1659)
  - Pierson Sage Square (Box 158, Folder 1660)
  - Pillsbury Bequest (Box 158, Folder 1661)
  - Placement Bureau, President's statement (Box 158, Folder 1662)
  - Planting, Bureau of; Cromie, George A. (Box 158, Folder 1663)
  - Po (Box 158, Folder 1664)
  - Pr (Box 159, Folder 1665-1667)
  - Preparatory schools (Box 159, Folder 1668)
  - President's Office (Box 159, Folder 1669)
  - President's Report (Box 159, Folder 1670-1672)
  - Primate Biology, Anthropoid Experiment Station
    - Advisory Committee, 1924-1931 (Box 159, Folder 1673)
    - Advisory Committee, 1928-1931 (Box 159, Folder 1674)
    - Advisory Committee, undated (Box 160, Folder 1675-1677)
    - Annual Report, First, 1929-1930 (Box 160, Folder 1678)
    - Annual Report, Second, 1930-1931 (Box 160, Folder 1679)
    - Annual Report, Third, 1931-1932 (Box 160, Folder 1680)
    - Annual Report, Fourth, 1933-1934 (Box 160, Folder 1681)
    - Annual Report, Fifth, 1933-1934 (Box 160, Folder 1682)
    - Annual Report, Sixth, 1934-1935 (Box 160, Folder 1683-1684)
    - Annual Report, Seventh, 1935-1936 (Box 160, Folder 1685)
    - Committee on Appraisal and Recommendation (Box 161, Folder 1686-1867)
    - Views (photographs) (Box 161, Folder 1688)
  - Primate Biology, Laboratories of (Box 161, Folder 1689-1693)
  - Princeton (Box 161, Folder 1694-1695)
  - Pritchett, Henry S. (Box 162, Folder 1696)
  - Professorships, Proposed Memorial (Box 162, Folder 1697)
  - Progressive Education Association (Box 162, Folder 1698)
  - Prohibition (Box 162, Folder 1699)
  - Protein research (Box 162, Folder 1700)
  - Provost (Box 162, Folder 1701)
  - Psychology, Child Clinic-Gesell, A. (Box 162, Folder 1702-1703)
  - Psychology, Child Clinic-Gesell, A., photographic correspondence (Box 162, Folder 1704)
  - Psychology, Child Clinic, Laura Spellman Rockefeller Memorial (Box 162, Folder 1705)
  - Psychology Department (Box 162, Folder 1706-1707)
  - Psychology, Institute of (Box 162, Folder 1708)
  - Psychology, Ninth International Congress (Box 163, Folder 1709-1712)
  - Psychology papers (Box 163, Folder 1713)
  - Psychology, Test report, Spencer, L.T.-Anderson, J.E. (Box 163, Folder 1714)
  - Publicity (Box 163, Folder 1715)
  - Publications of the University Council, Committee on (Box 163, Folder 1716)
  - Public utilities economics (Box 163, Folder 1717)
  - Pugsley, C.D., International Relations (Box 163, Folder 1718-1719)
  - Q (Box 164, Folder 1720)
  - Quality Credits Committee (Box 164, Folder 1721)
  - R (Box 164, Folder 1722-1723)
  - Rabbinical literature (Box 164, Folder 1724)
  - Radio broadcasting (Box 164, Folder 1725)
  - Re (Box 164, Folder 1726-1727)
  - Reading periods (Box 164, Folder 1728)
  - Real estate (Box 164, Folder 1729)
  - Recitation schedule, College and freshman year (Box 164, Folder 1730)
  - Registration figures including some figures for Yale men entering other schools on graduation (Box 164, Folder 1731)
  - Rel (Box 164, Folder 1732)
  - Reo (Box 164, Folder 1733)
  - Research at Yale (Box 164, Folder 1734-1735)
  - Research title (Associate, Fellow, Assistant) (Box 165, Folder 1736)
  - Research work (Box 165, Folder 1737)
  - Retiring allowances, Insurance and Annuity Association (Box 165, Folder 1738)
  - Rettger, Leo F. (Box 165, Folder 1739)
  - Reynolds, Horatio M. (Box 165, Folder 1740)
  - Reynolds, James Bronson (Box 165, Folder 1741)
  - Rhodes Scholarship (Box 165, Folder 1742-1748)
  - Ri (Box 166, Folder 1749-1750)
  - Richmond, George Chalmers (Box 166, Folder 1751)
  - Ripley, Alfred (Box 166, Folder 1752-1753)
  - Ro (Box 166, Folder 1754-1755)
  - Robinson, Edward S. (Box 167, Folder 1756)
  - Rochester, University of (Box 167, Folder 1757)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, The (Box 167, Folder 1758-1759)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, The Quarterly Bulletin (Box 167, Folder 1760-1764)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, The Scientific Directors of the International Health Division, minutes (Box 168, Folder 1765-1767)
  - Rockefeller, John D. Jr. (Box 168, Folder 1768)
  - Rockefeller, John D. III (Box 168, Folder 1768)
  - Rockefeller Memorial, Laura Spelman (Box 168, Folder 1769)
  - Roe (Box 168, Folder 1770)
  - Rogers, James Gamble (Box 168, Folder 1771)
  - Rogers, James Grafton (Box 168, Folder 1772)
  - Romance Language Department (Box 168, Folder 1773-1775)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Box 169, Folder 1776)
  - Roosevelt Memorial Association (Box 169, Folder 1777)
  - Ros (Box 169, Folder 1778-1779)
  - Rosenbluth case (Box 169, Folder 1780)
  - Rosenwald Fund (Box 169, Folder 1781)
  - Rostovtzeff, Michael (Box 169, Folder 1782)
  - Ru (Box 169, Folder 1783-1784)
  - Ruml, Beardsley (Box 169, Folder 1785)
  - Russell, George E. (Box 169, Folder 1786)
  - Ryerson, Edward L. Jr. (Box 169, Folder 1788)
  - S (Box 170, Folder 1789-1790)
  - St. Paul's School, Drury, Samuel, Shattuck, Frederick (Box 170, Folder 1791)
  - St. Stephen's College, Bell, Bernard I. (Box 170, Folder 1792)
  - Salter, James Arthur (Box 170, Folder 1793)
  - Saturday Review, The (Box 170, Folder 1794)
  - Sc (Box 170, Folder 1795)
  - Schepp, Leopold Foundation (Box 170, Folder 1796)
  - Schley, Reeve (Box 170, Folder 1797)
  - Schm (Box 170, Folder 1798)
  - Scholarship aid for sons of faculty members (Box 170, Folder 1799)
  - Scholarship, Alumni Advisory Board Committee (Box 170, Folder 1800)
  - Scholarships, fellowships (Box 170, Folder 1801)
    See also: box 15, folder 170-172
  - Scholarships for foreign students (Box 170, Folder 1802)
  - Schools and deans (Box 170, Folder 1803)
  - Schu (Box 170, Folder 1804)
  - Science Advisory Board (Box 171, Folder 1805)
  - Science and Enginnering in the University, Committee to Investigate Problems of (Box 171, Folder 1806)
  - Scott, John Alvin Bequest (Box 171, Folder 1807)
  - Scott, Walter, manuscript material (Box 171, Folder 1808)
  - Se (Box 171, Folder 1809)
  - Seashore, Carl E. (Box 171, Folder 1810)
  - Secretary of the University (Box 171, Folder 1811)
  - Sectioning on the basis of ability (Box 171, Folder 1812)
  - Semitic Languages Department (Box 171, Folder 1813)
  - Service Bureaus, University (Box 171, Folder 1814)
  - Seymour, Charles (Box 171, Folder 1815-1817)
  - Seymour, Charles, budget materials, 1928-1930 (Box 171, Folder 1818)
  - Seymour, George Dudley (Washington chairs) (Box 171, Folder 1819)
  - Sh (Box 172, Folder 1820)
  - Sheffield Scientific School
    - Administration, Building and Transportation (Box 172, Folder 1821)
    - Board of Trustees (Box 172, Folder 1822)
    - Correspondence and memoranda (Box 172, Folder 1823-1827)